<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacking on Bill Farmer</title>
    <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/categories/hacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacking on Bill Farmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2017 Bill Farmer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 11:57:27 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/categories/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Text Search</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/android-text-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 11:57:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/android-text-search/</guid>
      <description>The Android guide for Search Overview is oriented towards searching external content rather than text. There is a mention of Using the Search Dialog. However all the bits you need are there. To get a search dialog in the toolbar that pops up when needed, you need a seach item in the menu. It should be the first item, unless there is a good reason otherwise.
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34; encoding=&amp;#34;utf-8&amp;#34;?&amp;gt; &amp;lt;menu xmlns:android=&amp;#34;http://schemas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Emacs in Android Development</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/using-emacs-in-android-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:51:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/using-emacs-in-android-development/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got a folder full of country flags which I have renamed using scripts so the names correspond to currency symbols. I want an integer array with references to the flags as android resources. This can be automated using emacs.
I get a list of the file names into a buffer using find, which I then open with emacs.
% find src/ -name flag* &amp;gt; data/sym-flags.lst They are already sorted, but just to make sure I use M-x sort-lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown OpenStreetMap Maps</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/markdown-openstreetmap-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 12:59:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/markdown-openstreetmap-maps/</guid>
      <description>There does not seem to be a convention for showing maps or co-ordinates in Markdown, but almost anything gets put in square brackets [&amp;lt;anything&amp;gt;].
I had a request from Marco the other day to put OpenStreetMap maps in my Diary app using
 [&amp;lt;lat&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;lng&amp;gt;]  syntax. So I did a bit of a search to see if there was a convention in Markdown for co-ordinates and couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything. So we seem to have broken new ground here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Related Content working</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/getting-related-content-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/getting-related-content-working/</guid>
      <description>The latest release of Hugo includes Related Content, which I thought would be nice to add to my blog. However the docs, although they show you how to set it up, don&amp;rsquo;t explain how it works. To find that out, I had to look at the various threads on the Hugo forums.
There are four parts - you need to create a new partial template in layouts/partials/related.html containing something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a calendar event in android</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/adding-a-calendar-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 14:54:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/adding-a-calendar-event/</guid>
      <description>The android docs for the Calendar Provider are quite useful, but recommend the use of an AsyncQueryHandler for querying or adding events to calendars in an asynchronous thread. However the AsyncQueryHandler docs don&amp;rsquo;t include much guidance as to how to use it.
To add an entry to an android calendar you first have to find out the calendar id using an asynchronous query on the calendars table.
// QueryHandler public class QueryHandler extends AsyncQueryHandler { private static final String TAG = &amp;#34;QueryHandler&amp;#34;; // Projection arrays  private static final String[] CALENDAR_PROJECTION = new String[] { Calendars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whatever-o-meter revisited</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/whatever-o-meter-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 11:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/whatever-o-meter-revisited/</guid>
      <description>I wrote the whatever-o-meter about five years ago in PHP and Javascript as a Wordpress plugin. As I have migrated my blog to Hugo, I thought to have a go at reimplementing it. The exporter I used made a good job of translating the Wordpress custom fields to Hugo front matter parameters. I had to put dashes in quotes, otherwise they get interpreted as [&amp;lt;nil&amp;gt;].
intro:Pleaseanswerthefollowingquestionscarefullyandtruthfully.question:-YouarelyinginbedonMondaymorning...result:-&amp;#39;%d percent, Perhaps you should consider emigration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating this blog from Wordpress</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/migrating-blog-from-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/migrating-blog-from-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>I have got fed up with Wordpress. It required constant updates, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t work automatically on Sourceforge developer web, and it&amp;rsquo;s slow, especially in admin mode. I came across a reference to Hugo while following up on something unrelated, so I decided to investigate.
I looked for migration tools, and found two:
 Exitwp, which reads a Wordpress export xml file and converts to Jeckyll WordPress to Hugo Exporter, which is a Wordpress plugin and exports to Hugo  I found a blog post from Justin Dunham documenting migrating his blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving content uris in android</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/resolving-content-uris-in-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 10:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/resolving-content-uris-in-android/</guid>
      <description>If you write an android app that handles images or any other sort of file your app may be required to deal with &amp;lsquo;content&amp;rsquo; uris (content://). There is a very useful utility which resolves these into &amp;lsquo;file&amp;rsquo; uris (file:///) FileUtils.java. This contains one external reference to LocalStorageProvider, which can be resolved by removing the function isLocalStorageDocument() and references to it.
// import com.ianhanniballake.localstorage.LocalStorageProvider;  // ...  /** * @param uri The Uri to check.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling run time changes in Android</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/handling-run-time-changes-in-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 18:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/handling-run-time-changes-in-android/</guid>
      <description>Two articles, Handling Configuration Changes and Handling Configuration Changes with Fragments recommend the use of fragments to retain data and background tasks in Android during the life of an app. There are two problems with this:
 An android fragment is quite a complex heavyweight object to use just for retaining data and possibly a background task, and the fragment management is not simple. Fragments are not retained if the associated activity is discarded by calling finish().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Emacs as an IDE</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/using-emacs-as-an-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 13:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/using-emacs-as-an-ide/</guid>
      <description>I had to learn Emacs on Unix many years ago as it was at that time the only development environment for Smallworld Magik. Having learnt it, I have stuck with it as it provides a consistent platform for editing source code and building applications in as many computer languages and platforms as I have used and many more I haven&amp;rsquo;t. It is the only source code editor I have used that always gets the indentation and syntax highlighting right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading a Moto G</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/upgrading-a-moto-g/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 20:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/upgrading-a-moto-g/</guid>
      <description>I got myself a refurbished Moto G phone a while ago. It came with Android Kitkat 4.4.4, complete with Moto bloat. I had already put Cyanogenmod on my tablet, so I installed Cyanogenmod 11, android 4.4.4 on it, in accordance with the instructions on the wiki, no problem. That got rid of the bloat and allows fine control of app snooping via Privacy Guard in the settings.
When I first installed Cyanogenmod, I had to use an unofficial build, as an official build for Kitkat 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/upgrading-to-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 19:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/upgrading-to-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the Windows 10 preview, I thought it was a pain in the backside, so I have delayed upgrading from Windows 7 until the last minute when I got the countdown notification. I have been running a slightly dodgy copy of Windows 7 for a long time, so I was somewhat surprised when, out of the goodness of their hearts, Microsoft said I could have an activated copy of Windows 10 for free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resurrecting a netbook as a web server</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/resurrecting-a-netbook-as-a-web-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 19:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/resurrecting-a-netbook-as-a-web-server/</guid>
      <description>When I got fed up with Windows XP on my netbook, I tried windows 7 on it, but it was barely usable. So I tried Windows 7 Starter which was better. I upgraded it to Home Premium, which was OK at first, but slowed down as it got clagged up with updates.
That was it until recently, when I read an article about putting Windows 10 on one. I didn&amp;rsquo;t try that, but I did try Linux Mint on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Mac OSX apps using command line tools</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/build-mac-osx-apps-using-command-line-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 17:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/build-mac-osx-apps-using-command-line-tools/</guid>
      <description>You will need to install the Xcode command line tools, you don&amp;rsquo;t need the Xcode app. The easiest way to do this is to attempt to build an app like emacs by typing ./configure on the command line. A dialog box will pop up asking if you want to download and install the tools.
Xcode now uses the LLVM CLang compiler and documentation is exceedingly hard to find. You can type gcc -help or clang -help on the command line to get some info.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read iBook books on an Android tablet</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/read-ibook-books-on-an-android-tablet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 16:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/read-ibook-books-on-an-android-tablet/</guid>
      <description>You will need to install Calibre to make the books usable, and the books must be DRM free.
There are two ways to do this:
 If you have a Mac or Hackintosh you can find your books in ~/Library/Containers/com.apple.BKAgentService/Data/Documents/iBooks/Books, in what appears to be epub files but are really folders with numeric names. Copy the ones you want to somewhere accessible, like ~/Books, and zip the contents of each folder, not the folder itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install OSX El Capitan on a PC (MBR)</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/install-osx-el-capitan-on-a-pc-mbr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 11:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/install-osx-el-capitan-on-a-pc-mbr/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  A real Mac or Hackintosh A spare disk drive &amp;#8211; at least 8Gb, preferably USB An 8Gb or larger USB stick The Install OSX El Capitan.app from the App Store A disk partition to install in  Install on spare disk drive Connect your spare drive to your PC. Use the method described here to build the El Capitan install USB stick and install OSX using the GPT partition scheme on your spare disk drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Linux Mint Root Partition</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/move-linux-mint-root-partition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 13:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/move-linux-mint-root-partition/</guid>
      <description>I recently added a new disk drive to my workstation and, as part of reorganising, wanted to move the Linux Mint root partition from one disk to another. Naturally I googled duckied it and found a certain amount of useful info.
I used gnuparted to copy the partition from one disk to another. The standard method to reinstall grub on a partition so it will boot appears to be to mount it and use grub-install with the &amp;#8211;boot-directory option like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handlers in Android</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/handlers-in-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 15:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/handlers-in-android/</guid>
      <description>Using a handler to return results from a worker thread This has taken me quite a while to put together. There are throw-away remarks in the Android docs about this, but no useful examples. You want to get the results back from a worker thread to your main activity so you can do stuff with them. There are several parts to this.
 The main activity implements Handler.Callback, and has a handleMessage function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Engine Optimisation (SEO)</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/search-engine-optimisation-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 18:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/search-engine-optimisation-seo/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t worried too much about search engines since I set this site up. I registered it with Google initially, and after a few days it appeared in the results, so that was good enough for me. If you search for Old Shoreham Buccaneers, or a subset of that, the Buccaneers site appears high in the results, job done.
Since I published a recipe based on the BBC TV programme Italy Unpacked about a month ago, I have been getting a lot of hits on the Recipes page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/fast-fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 12:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/fast-fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a java tuner app a few years ago, so I needed a Fast Fourier Transform to do the frequency detection. I found a fairly simple implementation in java on the web somewhere, can&amp;rsquo;t remember where, tried it, and it worked fine. The frequency detection algorithm comes from The Dsp Dimension.
A few years later I ported it to windows, added a few gizmos for tuning accordions and put it on Google Code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer contacts from iPhone to Android</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/transfer-contacts-from-iphone-to-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 17:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/transfer-contacts-from-iphone-to-android/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using an old iPhone 3G, and I&amp;rsquo;ve got myself a new Android phone. First off, I googled DuckDuckGo&amp;rsquo;d how to transfer my contacts and found lots of suggestions. First, I tried My Contacts Backup, but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t install on the iPhone.
So I synced the contacts with my Hackintosh using iTunes, exported the contacts to a vCard file, transferred it to the phone by email and imported the file to the Contacts app on the phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 13:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/c/</guid>
      <description>I made a vow about 20 years ago not to attempt to learn C++, when a colleague went on a C++ course. I did buy a C++ book, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that useful. I have looked at the source of various C++ programs over the years to attempt to find out how they worked. I have, until recently, invariably found that the code that does something useful is either hidden in include files, or buried so deep in obscure code that just seems to create and do strange things with various objects, that I have been unable to find it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Collections</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/java-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 12:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/java-collections/</guid>
      <description>I find Java Collections frustrating and insane. I have been through this loop on several occasions. I decide I want a list to do whatever. So I look up List in the docs and find it&amp;rsquo;s an interface, ie: roll yer own. So I look down the hierarchy and find AbstractList, which is abstract, again: roll yer own. So finally I get to ArrayList which might do the job, but the docs aren&amp;rsquo;t too clear, so I try it and it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download streamed video</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/download-streamed-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 16:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/download-streamed-video/</guid>
      <description>Online video providers tend to stream the video to a javascript player, so making it extremely difficult to capture the video. This blog explains a method using Chrome to spoof the user agent string, pretending to be an iPad. Unfortunately, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work any more in the latest version of Chrome.
So I tried installing a user agent spoofing plugin in Firefox. It seemed to work, but the video didn&amp;rsquo;t play, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the url.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency, Threads, Semaphores and Mutexes</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/concurrency-threads-semaphores-and-mutexes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 15:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/concurrency-threads-semaphores-and-mutexes/</guid>
      <description>I have written several applications in both Java and C that involve running an audio thread in the background to read or write audio from or to the audio system while displaying the results and interacting with the user in the foreground. I have used lots of threads, but never a semaphore or mutex apart from the odd boolean variable.
This issue is reminiscent of back in the day when you actually had or could get a circuit diagram of your computer and could understand it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading WordPress</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/upgrading-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 11:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/upgrading-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>This site has the firewall set up so that the web server has no external access. This means that I can&amp;rsquo;t use the usual WordPress update mechanism to keep it up to date. I use FileZilla for maintaining the server, and I recently discovered you can use drag and drop to move stuff around remotely.
So my easy WordPress upgrade method is:
 Download the latest zip file and unzip it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haskell</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/haskell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 15:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/haskell/</guid>
      <description>I read an article recently about how amazingly efficient functional programming, and Haskell in particular is. So I thought I&amp;rsquo;s give it a go and see how I got on.
You can try it out in your browser: http://tryhaskell.org
λ let factorial n = product [1..n] in factorial 99 9332621544394415268169923885626670049071596826438162146859 2963895217599993229915608941463976156518286253697920827223 7582511852109168640000000000000000000000 :: (Enum a, Num a) =&amp;gt; a λ  Pretty impressive! So I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try a simple web application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SlimStat</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/slimstat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 16:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/slimstat/</guid>
      <description>When I first set up this web site, I looked for a simple web analytics program so that I could see if anyone actually looked at it. After faffing about with a couple of well known open source packages, I decided that they were way over the top by several orders of magnitude. Then I found SlimStat. However it appears to be no longer actively maintained, which it why the previous link is via the Way Back Machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Wifi</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/raspberry-pi-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 20:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/raspberry-pi-wifi/</guid>
      <description>When I got my Pi some months ago I bought a wifi adapter for it, as you do. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to work reliably in Raspbian, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even try in Arch Linux. So I tested the adapter on my windoze box, and it worked just fine, and I tried it with Linux and it worked just fine, so I put it in the &amp;lsquo;too hard&amp;rsquo; box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 18:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/python/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve studiously avoided Python up till now, even though it appears to be fairly popular, because it violates the first law of compiler design: &amp;lsquo;Blank space shalt not be significant except to separate tokens where necessary.&amp;rsquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s why you can minimise a lengthy JavaScript script like jQuery to one enormously long line and it still works just fine.
But, she-who-shall-be-ignored (self categorisation) decided she wanted to enter an advent calender competition which involved checking a web page to see if your name has come up and sending an email if it does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whatever-o-meter</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/whatever-o-meter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 18:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/whatever-o-meter/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Whatever-o-meter is a WordPress and Hugo plugin that shows a tachometer-like dial with a pointer, asks a series of predefined questions which are answered by moving a slider, shows one of several predefined results, and moves the tacho pointer to a position determined by the value of the result. The project is on Github.
Documentation Whatever-o-meter uses the shortcode [whatever-o-meter] or {{&amp;lt;whatever-o-meter&amp;gt;}} to insert the whatever-o-meter display into the page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>