<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recipes on Bill Farmer</title>
    <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/categories/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recipes on Bill Farmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2019 Bill Farmer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 11:55:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/categories/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Draught Hash Brown</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/draught-hash-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 11:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/draught-hash-brown/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, in a hotel in Hollywood, we thought the breakfast was a bit overpriced. Someone suggested the Dunkin&#39; Donut across the road, so over we went. In there the guy was offering bacon, egg over easy, and hash brown for 99¢. I was intrigued with the hash brown, he just took a handful of grated potato from a plastic bag and chucked it on the griddle plate.
Ingredients  Grated potato Vegetable cooking oil  Method  Put some cooking oil in a hot medium sized skillet Grate your potatoes and put them in the pan Cook until browned underneath and turn over Serve when browned on the reverse side  Goes extremely well with bacon and eggs and the trimmings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Meatball Wiggleoni</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/australian-meatball-wiggleoni/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 17:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/australian-meatball-wiggleoni/</guid>
      <description>This is an adaptation of a recipe by our daughter&amp;rsquo;s Australian fiancee. His version was a way of getting vegetables into his kids by hiding them in meat sauce. This adaptation uses meatballs instead of mince.
Ingredients  Meatballs Tomatoes, chopped Tomato paste Olive oil Oregano Onions, chopped Garlic, chopped Carrots, chopped Celery, chopped Cabbage, chopped Fusilli pasta  Method  Fry or cook the meatballs in the oven, keeping them warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Swedish Meatballs</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/not-swedish-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 19:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/not-swedish-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Meatballs are sometimes on offer at our local supermarket, so what can you do with them apart from meatball curry or meatballs with spaghetti? What about swedish meatballs? Well we didn&amp;rsquo;t like the sound of the creamy gravy or sauce they are supposed to be served with and decided that Truly Evil Onion Gravy was the way to go.
Ingredients  Meatballs Frozen or fresh peas Truly Evil Onion Gravy  Method  Start the gravy first as it takes a while to render the onions down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marion&#39;s Banana and Walnut Cake</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/banana-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/banana-cake/</guid>
      <description>This cake is delicious, quick and easy to make.The amount of sugar is reduced because the banana has natural sweetness. I have substituted rapeseed oil for cooking margarine as it is a healthier option. Using this method you do not need a food processor.
Ingredients  225g (8oz) self raising flour 1 level teaspoon baking powder 55g (2oz) demerara sugar 2 large ripe bananas 55g (2oz) walnut pieces 55g (2oz) sultanas 2 eggs 2 tablespoons rapeseed oil milk to mix   20cm cake tin (or similar)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushrooms and Soy Sauce</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/post/mushrooms-and-soy-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 16:43:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/post/mushrooms-and-soy-sauce/</guid>
      <description>When I was working for the electric light company in Hove, many years ago, the canteen ladies frequently served up, as part of a buffet, sliced raw mushrooms in soy sauce. Tasty side dish with a salad or buffet.
Ingredients  Thinly sliced mushrooms Dark soy sauce  Method  Thinly slice the mushrooms into a bowl Sprinkle over the soy sauce Leave for a while for the sauce to soak into and soften the mushrooms  I have not seen this elsewhere or online, so I assume that the canteen ladies came up with the idea themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Mash</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/interesting-mash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 10:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/interesting-mash/</guid>
      <description>This is similar to Vegetables cooked in olive oil, except mashed or whipped with a fork. Parsnips are difficult to grate, the softer outer part can be peeled off with a vegetable peeler, and the harder inner core sliced thinly.
Ingredients  Sliced onions Potatoes Carrots Parsnips/Swede/Turnips Cabbage/Spinach Olive oil  Method  Cover the bottom of a medium saucepan with oil Place a layer of sliced onions on the bottom Layer grated carrot, grated parsnip/turnip/swede, cubed potato and chopped cabbage/spinach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Tomatoes</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/green-tomatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 13:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/green-tomatoes/</guid>
      <description>If you grow your own tomatoes outside you will end up with green ones that aren&amp;rsquo;t going to ripen up anytime soon. The classic method for using them up is to make Green Tomato Chutney, which is quite easy. If the skins are tough, use a blender to liquidise them.
Green Tomato Chutney Ingredients  175g/6oz light brown sugar 150ml/5fl oz red wine vinegar 1 shallot or small onion, peeled, finely chopped 1 garlic clove, peeled, finely chopped 2cm/¾in piece fresh root ginger, peeled, finely grated 1 red chilli, finely chopped 125g/4½oz sultanas 600g/1lb 5oz green tomatoes, quartered  Method  Heat the sugar in a frying pan until the sugar melts and caramelises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boiled Beef and Carrots</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/boiled-beef-and-carrots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 11:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/boiled-beef-and-carrots/</guid>
      <description>This method can be used for any cut of beef but works very well for brisket or braising steak.
Ingredients  Brisket joint 4-6 chopped onions 3-4 large carrots Olive oil Black pepper Bay leaves  Method  Place joint in large covered casserole or saucepan with a couple of bay leaves Grind some black pepper over the joint and pour over some olive oil Surround the meat with chopped onions and chopped carrots Put on the lid and place in a slow oven for about 4-5 hours Enjoy with roast potatoes, parsnips and green veg  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Tomatoes</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/baked-tomatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 12:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/baked-tomatoes/</guid>
      <description>On a holiday staying at the Atlantic Hotel, St Mary&amp;rsquo;s there seemed to be a different breakfast chef nearly every day. One of them had a novel way of preparing tomatoes for an English breakfast.
Ingredients  Tomatoes Oregano Olive oil  Method  Take the stems off the tomatoes and place them upside down in a baking tin. They should be stable upside down. Cut a cross in the bottom of each one, put a few drops of oil on each one and sprinkle over some oregano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Whole Mushrooms</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/fried-whole-mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 12:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/fried-whole-mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>Just a more interesting way of preparing mushrooms than chopping them up.
Ingredients  Mushrooms Olive oil  Method  Keep the mushrooms whole, even if they have long stems. Put some oil in a skillet over a medium heat and place the mushrooms cap down in the pan with the stems sticking up. Add a couple of drops of oil to the inside of the cap of each mushroom. When the caps are browned tip them on their sides or turn them over depending on the length of the stems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corned Beef Chili</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/corned-beef-chili/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 10:47:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/corned-beef-chili/</guid>
      <description>This is an instant meal ideal for taking as part of a grub kit on holiday for when you arrive. I know you are not supposed to put red beans in chili, but you never get offered it without. I know you are supposed to make chili with chopped steak, not mince, let alone corned beef. A meal for four.
Ingredients  Tin of corned beef Tin of red beans Tin of chopped tomatoes Packet of chili mix Olive oil  Method  Warm up a large skillet over a gentle heat with some olive oil and add the corned beef, breaking it up into chunks When the corned beef has warmed through, add the chili mix and the tin of tomatoes Stir gently, drain the tin of red beans and add to the pan Allow to simmer, stirring to prevent sticking, until well heated through Meanwhile, cook a pot of boiled rice Serve with the rice and possibly some mango chutney  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Butter Beans in Tomato Sauce</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/butter-beans-in-tomato-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 09:49:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/butter-beans-in-tomato-sauce/</guid>
      <description>We have been offered this in many Greek tavernas, especially the ones with what&amp;rsquo;s on offer displayed in a glass counter. On a trip to Alonnisos we saw big tins of these, called Gigantes, at the back of a taverna/supermarket/cash &amp;amp; carry that seemed to stock everything.
Ingredients  Tin of butter beans Tin of chopped tomatoes 2 cloves of garlic, chopped 2 onions, chopped Oregano Olive oil  Method  Fry the onions, garlic and oregano in olive oil in a medium sized skillet until soft Add the tin of chopped tomatoes, stir, and allow to simmer gently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thai Red Curry with Noodles</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/thai-red-curry-with-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 14:51:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/thai-red-curry-with-noodles/</guid>
      <description>This is rather unconventional, but we like it as a change from fried rice. Lidl conveniently stock the red curry paste, coconut milk and Chinese noodles. Enough for four.
Ingredients  2 or 3 garlic cloves, chopped 2 or 3 large onions, chopped 2 or 3 carrots, grated 2 or 3 tomatoes, chopped Whatever green veg is to hand, green, red, or white cabbage, chopped Mushrooms, chopped, if available Chicken, pork, fish, or whatever is available, chopped 1/2 packet Chinese noodles 1/3 jar red curry paste 1 tin coconut milk 1 tbsp olive oil  Method  Place the onions, garlic, carrots, green veg and meat in a wok with the olive oil over a low heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrot and Coriander Soup</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/carrot-and-coriander-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 17:51:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/carrot-and-coriander-soup/</guid>
      <description>Tasty soup that makes a nice lunch for two.
Ingredients  3 large carrots, grated 1 large onion, chopped 2 garlic cloves, chopped Small bunch of coriander, chopped 1 tbsp olive oil Black pepper Milk  Method  Place the onions, garlic, carrots and coriander in a small pan with some olive oil and grind over some black pepper Heat gently over a low heat until the vegetables are soft Nearly cover with milk Allow to warm until the milk begins to froth Take off the heat and partially process with a blender so there are plenty of chunks of veg Serve with toast or crusty bread  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetables cooked in olive oil</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/vegetables-cooked-in-olive-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 10:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/vegetables-cooked-in-olive-oil/</guid>
      <description>This method can be used for cooking any selection of vegetables, the trick is to layer them with the slowest cooking, like green beans, carrots, and other root veg at the bottom of the pan, and the faster cooking, like broccoli, cabbage and spinach on top. A layer of sliced onions in the bottom of the pan melts down and steams the veg above.
Ingredients  Sliced onions Potatoes Carrots Whatever green veg is to hand Olive oil  Method  Cover the bottom of a medium saucepan with oil Place a layer of sliced onions on the bottom Layer sliced carrots, potatoes, and green veg in the pan Put on a low heat for about 20 minutes with the lid on until the veg is cooked to taste  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow cooked ox cheek</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/slow-cooked-ox-cheek/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 10:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/slow-cooked-ox-cheek/</guid>
      <description>Ox cheek is a tasty cut of beef, but it contains tough connective tissue which melts away when slow cooked.
Ingredients  Ox cheek 4-6 chopped onions 3-4 large carrots Olive oil Black pepper Bay leaves  Method  Put ox cheek in slow cooker and set to high heat Put a couple of bay leaves in the pot, grind black pepper over the meat and pour some olive oil over it Surround the meat with chopped onions and chopped carrots Put on the lid and allow to cook for a while When bubbling melted down onion and meat juices become visible around the meat, turn the heat down to low Allow to cook for 4-5 hours Enjoy with potatoes and green veg  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whole Broad Beans in Olive Oil</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/whole-broad-beans-in-olive-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 18:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/whole-broad-beans-in-olive-oil/</guid>
      <description>This is from a transport caff near the village of Pissouri, Cyprus many years ago. The pods need to be picked before the beans have fully developed and before the pods have grown a tough membrane around the beans. I have not seen beans this young for sale.
Ingredients  Young broad bean pods, Olive oil  Method  Wash and trim the bean pods and put in a suitably sized saucepan Add a glug of olive oil, cover and place on a low heat for about 10 minutes or so The pods will become soft and possibly brown a little depending on the heat  The transport caff served a bowl of these as a meal in it’s own right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venison and Chorizo Casserole</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/venison-and-chorizo-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 15:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/venison-and-chorizo-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g diced venison 75g chorizo, chopped 2 large onions, chopped 5 cloves garlic, crushed 2 red peppers, chopped 2 large tomatoes, chopped Flour Bay leaves 2 tsp paprika Olive oil Red wine Stock or stock cube and boiling water  Method  Add some olive oil to a casserole and put on a low heat Toss the venison pieces in flour and brown all over in the casserole Add the chorizo, garlic and onions and allow to cook until the onion is turning transparent Add the red peppers, bay leaves, paprika and tomatoes, put the lid on and allow to cook until the tomatoes look cooked Add the red win and stock, or use a stock cube and top up with boiling water Allow to simmer gently for about one and a half hours  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shoreham fish chowder</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/shoreham-fish-chowder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 15:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/shoreham-fish-chowder/</guid>
      <description>Hearty meal for four, use whatever fish is available.
Ingredients  Olive oil Two or three garlic cloves, chopped Two or three onions, chopped Two or three potatoes, cubed 150g mushrooms sliced 100g spinach, stems removed. Two tomatoes, chopped 300g smoked cod or haddock fillet, skinned and chopped 100g salmon fillet, skinned and chopped 100g prawns 1 tsp paprika 1 tsp turmeric Milk  Method  Cover the bottom of a large pan with olive oil and put on a low heat Add the garlic, onions, potatoes, mushrooms, spinach and tomatoes, tearing up any big spinach leaves Cover and allow to steam until the spinach has wilted and the potato cubes are cooked Add the fish , prawns, paprika and turmeric and give a good stir and shake to distribute the ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catalan slow cooked chicken</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/catalan-slow-cooked-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 10:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/catalan-slow-cooked-chicken/</guid>
      <description>This is based on a recipe in Asda magazine.
Ingredients  Chicken pieces – drumsticks, thighs, legs – whatever 3 onions, chopped 2 cloves of garlic, sliced Red and green pepper, chopped 6 tomatoes, chopped Bay leaves 1tsp paprika 1tsp turmeric 1tsp dried oregano Chicken stock pot Olive oil  Method  Put the chicken pieces in a slow cooker with bay leaves and turn on full to warm up. Fry the chopped onions, peppers and garlic in olive oil until soft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Rice</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/fried-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 14:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/fried-rice/</guid>
      <description>This is our version of Chinese take-away fried rice. Use whatever meat and vegetables are in the larder. Tasty meal for four
Ingredients  2 onions, chopped 2 cloves of garlic, chopped 2 carrots, grated 1/4 white cabbage, thinly sliced 1 1/2 cups of easy cook rice 250g chopped gammon ham 100g cooked prawns 100g petit pois 1 3/4 cups water or stock Vegetable oil  Method  Put a large dollop of oil into a large skillet or wok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pan fried lamb&amp;rsquo;s liver, bacon and chorizo</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/pan-fried-lambs-liver-bacon-and-chorizo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 17:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/pan-fried-lambs-liver-bacon-and-chorizo/</guid>
      <description>Back in the mid 70’s, I had to do some work at Kingston upon Thames Power Station. When I stopped for lunch, I found a little Greek restaurant opposite in a parade of shops and restaurants. That whole area, including the power station has since been redeveloped, and bears no resemblance. I had their lunch time offer of pan fried kidneys, probably with rice.
When I got home, I mentioned this to she who did most of the cooking at that time and she came up with something which became her kidney special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo Egg and Tomato Toasted Sandwich</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/chorizo-egg-and-tomato-toasted-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 11:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/chorizo-egg-and-tomato-toasted-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>This is a nice snack for two.
Ingredients  Two eggs Sliced chorizo or crispy bacon Four slices of bread Tomato thinly sliced Cheese sliced  Method  Toast two slices of bread and fry two eggs Meanwhile slice the tomato thinly Flip the eggs, otherwise the tomato won’t stay on top Layer chorizo slices, egg, tomato slices and cheese slices on each piece of toast Put the toast slices on heatproof plates and put under a hot grill to melt the cheese Toast the other two slices of bread When the cheese is melted take the plates out and press down the other slices of toast on top Slice the sandwiches in two diagonally  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow cooked lamb</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/slow-cooked-lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 11:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/slow-cooked-lamb/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is based on the mutton in a pot in this episode of Italy Unpacked. I have converted it to a slow cooker recipe, but it could be done in a casserole in the oven or in a earthenware pot next to a wood fire. Some of the ingredients are a compromise, for example Giorgio bought a kilo of rocket in the market. I couldn’t have got all that in the pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausages with Green Lentils</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/sausages-with-green-lentils/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 18:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/sausages-with-green-lentils/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is based on the sausages with lentils in this episode of Italy Unpacked on BBC 2. This is enough for three or four, depending on the number of sausages. You will need a medium sized pan to cook the lentils, and a large deep pan for the sausages, onions, and everything else.
Ingredients  One cup green lentils Two sticks celery, chopped Large garlic clove or two small, chopped Six or eight good quality sausages Two large onions, chopped 500g carton passata Olive oil  Method  Put lentils, chopped celery and garlic in a pot, cover with water, boil for five minutes, then simmer for about 30 minutes until tender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuffed Peppers</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/stuffed-peppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 12:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/stuffed-peppers/</guid>
      <description>Lunch for two.
Ingredients  4 bell peppers 1/2 cup cous cous 6-8 slices chorizo cut into four pieces 2-3 cloves garlic, sliced small onion, chopped 1/4 vegetable stock cube 1/2 tsp paprika 1/2 tsp oregano boiling water olive oil  Method  Trim the stems of the peppers, cut the tops off, and remove the seeds and pulp from inside. Cover the bottom of a small pan with oil and add the garlic, onion, chorizo, paprika and oregano, place on a gentle heat and cook until the onions are transparent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unobtainium</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/unobtainium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 11:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/unobtainium/</guid>
      <description>unob·ta·ni·um (unob-tayn-ium)
Ingredient not available on the shelf at your local major supermarket.
If you attempt to use any celebrity or TV chef recipe, you will find at least one ingredient is unobtainable locally. You will also find a healthy disregard of the cleaning up operation afterwards. Usually most of this nonsense can be safely ignored and locally available ingredients used instead, and the recipe converted from an N-pot recipe to a one-pot recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coarse Ratatouille</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/coarse-ratatouille/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 18:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/coarse-ratatouille/</guid>
      <description>This is slow cooked vegetables using whatever comes to hand.
Ingredients  Onions, sliced Potatoes, sliced Carrots, sliced Whatever else is going, sliced or chopped Oil Large heavy frying pan or skillet with lid  Method  Warm up your skillet and put a dollop of oil in it Arrange a layer of sliced onions, making sure to spread the oil around Next a layer of sliced potato Next a layer of sliced carrots Add layers of whatever else is to hand to fill up the pan Pour a bit more oil over the top Put the lid on and cook gently until the carrots are cooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faggots and Peas with Onion Gravy</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/faggots-and-peas-with-onion-gravy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 18:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/faggots-and-peas-with-onion-gravy/</guid>
      <description>When I was a teenager the chippy at Preston, Weymouth, Dorset used to serve faggots and peas with gravy in those aluminium foil containers that take-away Chinese used to come in. Enough for 2.
Ingredients  3-5 faggots Frozen or fresh peas Truly Evil Onion Gravy  Method  Start the gravy first as it takes a while to render the onions down. Once the onions are well done, put the faggots in a tin and place in a medium hot oven – 180° C, until they are starting to brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truly Evil Onion Gravy</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/truly-evil-onion-gravy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 18:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/truly-evil-onion-gravy/</guid>
      <description>Black onion gravy to go with faggots, sausages or whatever takes your fancy.
Ingredients  3 medium onions, sliced 1 tablespoon plain flour or cornmeal (polenta) 1/2 vegetable stock cube, crumbled Boiling water or cooking water from vegetables Vegetable oil  Method  Cover the bottom of a small pan with oil and place on medium heat. Put the onions in the pan and cook, stirring with a fork until reduced to brown/black sludge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabada Asturiana</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/fabada-asturiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 16:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/fabada-asturiana/</guid>
      <description>A highly flavoured Asturian version of pork and beans. Enough for four or more.
Ingredients  375g or thereabouts packet of dried butter beans 4-500g belly pork with or without skin, cut into chunks Smoked gammon hock, or 4-500g cooking bacon. If lucky, it’s possible to find a packet of cooking bacon that is just one big chunk of unsliced bacon by rooting through the supermarket shelf. 100-125g picante chorizo, cut into chunks Crushed black peppercorns Heaped teaspoon paprika Heaped teaspoon turmeric 2 bay leaves 4-5 garlic cloves, chopped 3-4 onions, chopped Olive oil Water  Method  Soak the beans overnight in plenty of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable Soup Plus</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/vegetable-soup-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 17:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/vegetable-soup-plus/</guid>
      <description>A vegetable soup with a bit of meat that’s full of flavour. Similar to leek and potato soup recipe. Make it into a meal with plenty of bread and butter. Enough for two, double the recipe for four.
Ingredients  1 tbsp olive oil 1 onion, chopped 1 small potato, cubed 1 clove garlic, crushed 1/2 a fresh chilli, if desired Additional vegetables as available: grated carrot, leek, courgette, cabbage, etc a few slices of chorizo or other tasty sausage, chopped Freshly ground black pepper Milk  Method  Heat the oil in a large pan and add the vegetables and sausage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/mexican-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 09:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/mexican-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>This is an adaptation of a recipe I saw recently in the Metro. Not Huevos Rancheros, but something else. The original recipe was most insistent that the black pepper be added to the pan, not the eggs, and the eggs should be stirred, not beaten.
Ingredients  Small potato, chopped Small onion, chopped Chili pepper, sliced Chorizo, chopped Tomato, chopped Fresh ground black pepper 2 eggs Oil  Method  Put some oil in a medium sized skillet or frying pan and warm up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clementine Cake</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/clementine-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 13:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/clementine-cake/</guid>
      <description>This is an adaptation of a Marguerite Patten recipe dated 1963. As adapted by She-who-shall-be-ignored, with additional chutney technique.
Ingredients Cake  7oz self raising flour 1/4tsp Baking powder 5oz margarine or butter 4oz golden granulated sugar 3 medium eggs 3 clementines, chopped up into small pieces and any pips removed  Icing  3oz Icing sugar 2oz margarine or butter  Method  Put the sugar and the chopped clementines in a small saucepan on a gentle heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doug&amp;rsquo;s Seafood Risotto</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/dougs-seafood-risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 18:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/dougs-seafood-risotto/</guid>
      <description>This is my interpretation of my brother’s risotto. This is in no way a conventional risotto recipe, but it works nicely. Hearty dinner for four.
Ingredients  2 cups of risotto rice Three or four onions, depending on size Three cloves of garlic A red pepper and a green pepper A punnet of mushrooms, approx 200g 350g approx of seafood selection Freshly ground black pepper Oregano A chicken stockpot Butter Water Olive oil  Method   Warm up a large saucepan with a good glug of olive oil in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Frittata</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/spanish-frittata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 16:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/spanish-frittata/</guid>
      <description>Another not so light lunch for two.
Ingredients  Two largish onions Four or five eggs, depending on size Chorizo, sliced Cheese, sliced Freshly ground black pepper Oil for cooking  Method  Warm up a large skillet or frying pan with some cooking oil in it. While the pan is warming slice the onions into rings and place in the pan. Whip up the eggs and grind some black pepper into them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta Picante</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/pasta-picante/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 14:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/pasta-picante/</guid>
      <description>We ate this in the Restaurante Terraza del Mar along the coast path from Puerto de la Cruz in Tenerife. This is my adaptation. Light lunch for two.
Ingredients  Pasta for 2, whatever you like Small fresh chilli Small onion Couple of cloves of garlic Freshly ground black pepper Oregano Olive oil Anything else you fancy, we put some grated carrot in ours  Method  Cook the pasta in boiling water and drain when done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish omelette</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/spanish-omelette/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 12:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/spanish-omelette/</guid>
      <description>A nice tasty potato and onion omelette for breakfast.
Ingredients  2 eggs medium sized potato, cubed small onion, chopped chorizo, sliced, if liked Fresh ground black pepper vegetable oil  Method  Warm up a medium sized cast iron skillet, or omelette pan with a smidgeon of oil in it. Tilt the pan to make sure the oil covers the bottom and sides While the pan is warming up, chop the potato and onions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leek and Potato Soup</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/leek-and-potato-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 17:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/blog/leek-and-potato-soup/</guid>
      <description>A vegetable soup that’s full of flavour. Make it into a meal with plenty of bread and butter. Enough for two, double the recipe for four.
Ingredients  1 tbsp olive oil 1 onion, chopped 125g/4oz potatoes, cubed 1 medium leek, chopped 1 clove garlic, crushed 1/2 a fresh chilli, if desired 1 small carrot, grated 350ml/3/4 pint milk and water salt and freshly ground black pepper  Preparation method  Heat the oil in a large pan and add the onions, garlic, carrot, potatoes and leeks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
